母亲哭了，
And the mother cried,
“这就是我在你眼中所看到的自己吗？”
"Is this myself I see, reflected in your eyes?"
女儿说，
And the daughter said,
“我看到的是我吗？你看到的是我吗？”
"Is it me I see, mirrored in yours?"
海伦娜。
Helena.
回来吧。
Come back.
当你回来的时候，她会让你做两倍的家务。
She's going to make you do twice as many chores when you get back.
我不介意这笔交易。
I don't mind the trade.
也许如果我们离开够久了，她就会忘记她疯了。
Maybe if we're gone long enough, she'll forget she's mad.
好吧。
Okay.
我们走慢点，小影子。
We'll walk slow, Little Shadow.
它就在这里。
It was here.
跑步还是走路？
Running or walking?
步幅比以前更大了。
The strides are wider than before.
在外面更深的地方。
And deeper on the outsides.
它在运行。
It was running.
为什么？
Why?
因为它害怕什么。
Because it was scared of something.
害怕什么？
Scared of what?
我们。
Us.
如果你害怕，
If you were afraid,
逃命，你会去哪里？
running for your life, where would you go?
没人能看到我的地方。
Where no one could see me.
是时候让你完成狩猎了。
It's time you finished the hunt.
如果我打偏了怎么办？
What if I miss?
那我们今晚就挨饿。
Then we go hungry tonight.
我没有发出任何声音。
I didn't make a sound.
你觉得发生了什么事？
So, what do you think happened?
它闻到了我的味道。
It smelled me.
你不需要火了。
You won't need the fire.
海伦娜，来拿你今天赚的钱。
Helena, come get what you earned today.
她总是生我的气。
She's always mad at me.
哦，你妈妈不能像我们一样看到幸福。
Oh, your mother can't see happiness like we do.
好吧。
Okay.
我很好。
I'm fine.
已经这么晚了。
It's getting late.
海伦娜，别再这样了。
Helena, no more.
剩下的在哪里？
Where's the rest of it?
现在免费了。
It's free now.
它把自己的腿咬下来了？
It chewed its own leg off?
为了生存，牺牲了一切必须的东西。
Sacrificed what it had to, to survive.
我什么时候才能像你一样把我的放在家里？
When can I keep mine in the house like you do?
当你像我一样是个好猎人的时候
When you're as good a hunter as I am.
这将永远不会发生。
Which will be never.
印记上写的是什么？
What do the marks say?
他们说，
They say,
“当你逃离一只愤怒的驼鹿时，
"When you're running from an angry moose,
当心低矮的树枝。
beware of low branches."
我听到它在哭。
I heard it crying.
她饿坏了。
She's starving.
好的，我们里面有一些碎屑。我们也许可以...
Well, we have some scraps inside. We could maybe--
当这些都消失了，会发生什么？
What happens when those are gone?
没有什么比生存的本能更纯洁的了。
There's nothing more pure than the instinct to survive.
狼毫无怜悯之心。
The wolf holds no pity.
只是想再活一天。
Just the desire to live another day.
如果你饿了，你会对狼做什么？
What would you do to the wolf, if you were starving?
你是它的猎物。
You're its prey.
我们都是。
We all are.
但是孩子呢？
But what about the baby?
将遭受痛苦，孤独而死。
Will suffer and die alone.
现在照我说的做，海伦娜。
Now, do what I say, Helena.
但如果-海伦娜，快走
- But if-- - Helena, move.
你必须永远保护你的家人。
You must always protect your family.
不用了。这是我独自一人的旅行之一。
Nah. This is one of my alone trips.
-但我能帮上忙-不，来吧.你该明白规矩。
- But I can help. - No, come on. You know the rules.
-我会给你一个惊喜的.-什么样的惊喜？
- I'll bring you back a surprise. - What kind of surprise?
有点意外，你得等一等才能知道是什么。
Kind of surprise you're gonna have to wait to find out what it is.
现在，到后面去。
Now, get on back there.
我很快就会回家的。
I'll be home soon.
很抱歉来找你麻烦。
Sorry to come ridin' in on you.
你妈妈或爸爸在吗？
Is your mom or dad around?
嘿。
Hey.
希望我没有擅自闯入或什么的。
Hope I'm not trespassing or anything.
我不知道有人住在这么远的地方。
Didn't know anybody lived way out here.
在外面呆了几个小时，我都快晕过去了。我--
Been out for hours, and I got all spun around. I--
我找不到回到小路的路了。
I can't find my way back to the trail.
这里任何地方都没有信号。
No signal out here anywhere.
听着，如果你能指给我看--
Look, if you could just point me toward--
帮助!
Help!
请。在他回来之前。
Please. Before he gets back.
什么？
What?
我们这是在干嘛？
What are we doing?
你--你在干什么？
What are-- What are you doing?
上车，海伦娜。哇。坚持住。
Get on, Helena.[motorist] Whoa. Hang on.
-他很快就会回来。-谁？
- He'll be back soon. - Who?
求求你，我们得走了现在，-我...
- Please, we have to go. Now! - I--
-我不想走！-我不能就这么带你走
- I don't wanna go! - I can't just take you.
我甚至不确定我们在哪里。这就是为什么我...
I'm not even sure where we are. That's why I'm--
不是的！
No!
母亲!妈妈，住手！
Mother! Mother, stop!
母亲!妈妈，住手！停止播放!
Mother! Mother, stop! Stop!
海伦娜！-不！
-  Helena! - No!
父亲!
Father!
海伦娜？
Helena?
-父亲！-海伦娜？
-  Father! -  Helena?
不是的！
No!
停止播放!停止播放!
Stop! Stop!
来人呀!
Somebody!
看看谁醒了。
Look who's awake.
没关系的，海伦娜。
It's okay, Helena.
你妈妈就在隔壁房间。
Your mother's just in the next room.
我父亲在哪里？
Where's my father?
他不在这里。你现在安全了。
He's not here. You're safe now.
再也没有什么好怕的了。
There's nothing to be afraid of anymore.
别担心那件事。
Don't worry about that.
海伦娜。
Helena.
我们不应该在这里。我想回家。
We shouldn't be here. I want to go home.
-那不是我们的家-你做了什么？
- That wasn't our home. - What did you do?
你干什么了？
What did you do?
-我要爸爸.他不可能靠近我们。
- I want Father. He can't be near us.
再也不会了。
Ever again.
他带走了我，海伦娜。
He took me, Helena.
雅各布。
Jacob...
绑架了我，把我带到了树林里。
kidnapped me and took me to the woods.
你在说谎。
You're lying.
你是个骗子。你一直都是个骗子。
You're a liar. You have always been a liar.
父亲告诉我的。
Father told me.
别哭了！
Stop crying!
你不能这么做。
You're not allowed to do that.
我们需要让你母亲休息一下。
We need to let your mother rest.
就几分钟。
Just for a few minutes.
我们会没事的。海伦娜？
We'll be okay. Helena?
父亲?
Father?
-谁出局了？-是的
-  Who's out? -  Yeah.
好了，我们得走了。赶快。
Okay, we have to go. Come on.
你做得很好。赶快。
You did good. Come on.
好的，我们走这边。
Okay, let's go this way.
-他来了！-警察！不许动!
-  There he is! -  Police! Don't move!
我们要回家吗？
Are we gonna go home?
总有一天我们会的。
One day we will.
嘿!不许动!
Hey! Don't move!
离那女孩远点。
Back away from the girl.
不是的！趴在地上！
No! On your stomach!
现在!
Now!
他没有做错任何事。
He didn't do anything wrong.
让我看到你的手。
Let me see your hands.
我会来找你的，小影子。
I'll come find you, Little Shadow.
他在跑！我抓到他了！
He's running! I got him!
把手放在背后！-爸爸！
Hands behind your back! - Daddy!
开枪吧。
Shoot.
别跑了，玛丽戈德。
No running, Marigold.
嗨，甜心。
Hi, sweetie.
哈弗太太说她有自己的生活，如果你要迟到，
Mrs. Haver said she has a life of her own, and if you're gonna be late,
她要开始向你收取房租了。
she's gonna start charging you rent for me.
是吗？[玛丽戈德]这是什么意思？
She did, huh?[Marigold] What does that mean?
这意味着你很有价值，她认为我应该为你买单。
It means you are so valuable, she thinks I should pay for you.
你在这里发现了什么？
Whatcha got here?
我的科学项目。这是栖息地。[海伦娜]嗯。
My science project. It's a habitat.[Helena] Uh-huh.
栖息地？这个栖息地是给谁的？
Habitat? Who's the habitat for?
一只小鹿。
A baby deer.
它睡在这里，在岩石旁边，以确保它不被猎人猎杀。
It sleeps over here, beside the rocks, to keep it safe from hunters.
聪明的鹿。
Smart deer.
妈咪！
Mommy!
这是什么叶子？
What kind of leaf is this?
一颗核桃。
A walnut.
-从哪棵树？-你告诉我.
- From which tree? - You tell me.
那里。
There.
嗯-嗯。
Mm-hmm.
那棵树是什么？
And what's that tree?
一棵红橡树。
A red oak.
在我看来它不是红色的。
It doesn't look red to me.
它将在秋季举行。
It will be in the fall.
你看到那只鸟了吗？
Do you see the bird?
一只森林画眉鸟。
A wood thrush.
你怎么知道所有人的名字？
How do you know all the names?
如果你愿意，我可以教你。
I can teach you if you want.
我能看到一只兔子。
I can see a bunny rabbit.
哪里?
Where?
你必须稍微倾斜一下你的头。看到耳朵了吗？
You have to kind of tilt your head. See the ears?
哦，是啊。我看到它了。尾巴往下走吗？
Oh, yeah. I see it. With the tail down this way?
嗯。
Yeah.
这意味着我们是一体的。
It means that we're one.
一家人。
Family.
妈妈?
Mom?
我什么时候能吃到这个？
When can I have one of these?
直到你82岁的时候。
Not until you're 82 years old.
这是规则，记得吗？
That's the rule, remember?
那是不公平的。
That's not fair.
你年轻的时候就有了。
You got them when you were young.
我比你大很多，我希望我没有。
I was much older than you, and I wish I hadn't.
我喜欢他们。
I like them.
我喜欢你。
I like you.
爸爸回来了！
Daddy's home!
把你的东西放进去，亲爱的。
Put your stuff inside, sweetie.
我们要去校园参加爸爸的工作野餐。
We're going to the campus for Daddy's work picnic.
野餐吗-抱歉我们来晚了
-  Picnic? - Sorry we're late.
我忘了你今晚的事了。
I forgot about your thing tonight.
没关系。我们走吧。
That's all right. Let's just go.
我得换衣服了。你为什么不和她一起过去，我一会儿就来。
I have to change. Why don't you go on over with her, and I'll come later.
嗯，我们已经试过了。你从来没出现过。
Well, we've tried that. You never show.
我只是不擅长这些事情。-我也不是
I'm just not good - at those things. - Neither am I.
这就是为什么你要和我一起去。
Which is why you're coming with.
另外，你是我美丽的妻子，我想炫耀你。
Plus, you're my beautiful wife, and I want to show you off.
你知道吗，这很有趣。
You know, it's funny.
谢谢。
Thank you.
-嘿，你还好吗？-是的。
- Hey, you good? - Yeah.
玛丽戈德玩得开心吗？
Is Marigold having fun?
我不知道。最疯狂的是，
I don't know. The crazy thing is,
我的学生甚至不再试图隐藏它了。
my students don't even try to hide it anymore.
我整堂课的电话都响了。
Phones are going off my entire lecture.
好吧，为他们辩护，我听过你的一些演讲。
Well, in their defense, I have heard some of your lectures.
我喜欢那样。这很不寻常。
I love that. It's unusual.
-哦，谢谢.你是在这附近买的吗？
- Oh, thanks. Did you get it around here?
呃，在旧金山，我十几岁的时候。
Uh, in San Francisco, when I was a teenager.
你有一堆这样的人。
You have a bunch of them.
太多了。
Too many.
我不知道你是旧金山人。
I didn't know you're from San Francisco.
其他地方也是。-我们经常搬家。-你的父母是做什么的？
Other places too. - We moved around a lot. - What'd your parents do?
我父亲在保险业工作，我母亲有时做电话营销。
My father worked in insurance, my mom sometimes did telemarketing.
没有比这更无聊的了。
Doesn't get much more boring than that.
然后她拿出20个床垫，把它们放在豌豆上。
"Then she took 20 mattresses and laid them on the pea.
在这件事上，公主不得不躺了一整夜。
On this, the princess had to lie all night.
早上，有人问她睡得怎么样。
In the morning she was asked how she had slept.
公主说..。
And the princess said...
‘’哦，非常糟糕。‘’
'‘Oh, very badly.'"
到底怎么回事？我女儿在哪里？
What's going on? Where's my daughter?
海伦娜·埃里克森？
Helena Erikkson?
玛丽戈德在哪里？
Where's Marigold?
她不在这里。这不是关于她的。
She's not here. This isn't about her.
我是特别探员伊林。
I'm Special Agent Illing.
你在我家做什么？
What are you doing in my house?
-埃里克森女士。-我叫佩尔蒂埃.
- Ms. Erikkson. - My name is Pelletier.
在那之前，是琼斯，对吗？
Before that, it was Jones, correct?
然后是米切尔，在你把它从贝库姆改过来之后。
Then Mitchell, after you changed it from Bekkum.
但你是雅各布·霍尔布鲁克和贝丝·埃里克森的孩子。
But you were born to Jacob Holbrook and Beth Erikkson.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
你父亲雅各布·霍尔布鲁克。
Your father, Jacob Holbrook.
他和另一名囚犯昨晚越狱了
He and another prisoner escaped last night
在被送往阿尔杰监狱的过程中。
while being transported across the state line to Alger Penitentiary.
你最后一次和他说话是什么时候？
When's the last time you spoke to him?
当我十岁的时候。
When I was ten years old.
-他最近有没有试着联系你？-没有
- Has he tried to contact you recently? - No.
真的吗？一次都没有？
Are you sure? Not even once?
你本可以打电话给我的。你不需要来这里。
You could've called me. You didn't need to come here.
到底怎么回事？
What's going on?
你还好吗？
You okay?
你知道你父亲可能要去哪里吗？
Do you know where your father might be going?
你的父亲？
Y-Your father?
你不能就这样闯进我的房子。
You can't just come into my house.
我们的搜查令允许我们检查任何可能的通讯
Our warrant allows us to check for any possible communication
给你父亲或从你父亲那里。
to or from your father.
你为什么一直这么说？海伦娜的父亲
Why do you keep saying that? Helena's father--
他不知道我住在哪里，也不知道我姓什么，
He doesn't know where I live, doesn't know my last name,
对我一无所知。
doesn't know anything about me.
你的家人和朋友也是这样吗？你有没有--
And that's same for your family and friends? Have any of your--
我从没告诉过任何人雅各布·霍尔布鲁克是我父亲。
I've never told anyone Jacob Holbrook is my father.
所以，20年。
So, 20 years.
没有信，没有生日卡，什么都没有？
No letter, birthday card, anything?
不是的。
No.
我很困惑。
I'm confused.
我还以为你父母死于车祸呢。
I thought your parents died in a car accident.
我就是这么跟你说的。
That's what I told you.
还有霍尔布鲁克，他就是马什·金。就是刚刚逃走的那个。
And Holbrook, that's the Marsh King guy. The one that just escaped.
我在收音机里听到的。
I heard it on the radio.
没错。
That's right.
他来这里有风险吗？
Is there any risk of him coming here?
这就是我们想要找出的。
That's what we're trying to find out.
他不知道我住在哪里。
He doesn't know where I live.
哦，你不能太肯定这一点。
Oh, you can't be too sure of that.
天哪，海伦娜。你怎么能不告诉我呢？
Christ, Helena. How could you not have told me?
我告诉过你待在车里的，亲爱的。
I told you to stay in the car, sweetie.
-这些人是谁？-警察他们只是...
- Who are these people? - Police. They're just--
我要带她去。我晚些时候给你打电话。
I'm gonna take her. I'll call you later.
我们需要看看你的手机和你用过的电脑。
We're gonna need to see your phone and any computers you use.
如果运气好的话，你父亲很快就会被找到。
With any luck, your father will be found soon.
你不了解我父亲。
You don't know my father.
如果他能去野外，你就再也见不到他了。
If he makes it to the wild, you'll never see him again.
在这起在全国范围内臭名昭著的案件中，
In a case that received nationwide notoriety,
雅各布·霍尔布鲁克，所谓的“沼泽之王”，绑架了贝丝·埃里克森
Jacob Holbrook, the so-called "Marsh King," abducted Beth Erikkson
把她关了12年
and held her for 12 years
在密歇根州上半岛的荒野中，
in the wilderness of Michigan's Upper Peninsula,
直到她最终逃脱
until she eventually escaped
和她在囚禁期间生下的女儿在一起。
with the daughter she gave birth to while in captivity.
审判结束后，埃里克森很难适应正常生活
After the trial, Erikkson had difficulty adapting to normal life
很少在公共场合露面。
and was rarely seen in public.
不幸的是，她在四年前死于明显的自杀。
Tragically, she died four years ago in an apparent suicide.
嗯?
Yeah?
你们要回家吗？
You guys coming home?
我订了一间旅馆的房间过夜。玛丽在泳池里。
I grabbed a hotel room for the night. Mari's in the pool.
如果你愿意，我可以给她带些校服过来。
I could bring her over some school clothes, if you want.
我明天不让她进来，以防万一。
I'm keeping her out tomorrow, just in case.
我没想到会发生这种事。
I didn't think this would happen.
我会发现的吗？
That I'd find out?
不是的。我是说，我希望我...
No. I mean, I wish I--
玛丽在喊我。我得走了。
Mari's yelling for me. I gotta go.
小影子。
Little Shadow.
是时候检查我们的陷阱了。
Time to check our snares.
一个真正的猎人..。
And a real hunter...
需要一把真刀。
needs a real knife.
现在这是你的了。
This is yours now.
让我们看看你是怎么处理它的。
Let's see how you do with it.
嗨。
Hi.
我早些时候打过电话，但你没接。
I called earlier, but you didn't answer.
我不太会用手机。
I'm not great with phones.
这是轻描淡写的。
That's an understatement.
我看了新闻。
I saw the news.
我想我应该下来打个招呼。
Thought I'd shoot down and say hello.
你好，克拉克。
Hello, Clark.
也许在我回去之前喝一杯水。
Maybe grab a glass of water before I head back.
我知道你不想让我去拜访你，
I know you don't want me dropping in,
但我觉得现在一切都变了。
but I figured everything's changed a bit now.
猫已经从袋子里跑出来了。
Cat's outta the bag.
你丈夫对此反应如何？
How's your husband taking it?
不太好。
Not well.
他会回心转意。这只是个时间问题。
He'll come around. Just a matter of time.
小个子已经不是那么小了。
The little one's not so little anymore.
你母亲会很高兴见到她的。
Your mother would've loved to have met her.
我以为你会把玛丽戈德带回家一段时间，
I thought you might bring Marigold up home a while back,
至少在葬礼上是这样。
at least for the funeral.
那时她也不会遇到她。
She wouldn't have met her then either.
的确如此。
That's true enough.
那么，我想我是说我希望你早点来。
Then, I guess I meant I wish you woulda come sooner.
她会喜欢的。
She would've liked that.
他还在大学里干那份工作吗？
He still has that job at the college?
你还在做什么--什么都没变。
You still doing--Nothing's changed.
好吧。
Okay.
这不是我所看到的结果。
This is not how I saw this playing out.
抱歉，我现在不能这么做。
I'm sorry, I just can't do this right now.
好吧，至少媒体上没有报道。
Well, at least it's not in the press.
没人会把你和他放在一起。
No one's putting you with him.
只是想确定你不会担心一些事情。
Just wanted to make sure you weren't worried about things.
我没有。
I'm not.
你知道，在你13岁左右的时候有一段时间。
You know, there was a space when you were about 13 or so.
我以为我们有机会成为一个美好的小家庭，我们三个人。
I thought we had a shot at bein' a nice little family, the three of us.
从来不是我们三个，克拉克。
It was never the three of us, Clark.
她不想让我在她身边。
She didn't want me around.
当她看着我的时候，她看到了我的父亲。
When she looked at me, she saw my father.
你也是。
So did you.
不是的。
No.
你忘记了一些美好的日子。
You're forgetting some good days.
她爱你。
She loved you.
我还爱你。
I still love you.
我想念你。
I miss you.
但当然，也许有时我们在你身上看到了一点雅各布。
But sure, maybe sometimes we saw a little Jacob in you.
或许你在我身上看到的他还不够多。
Or maybe you never saw enough of him in me.
你是来解救这家伙的吗？[警官]不，我应该--
You here to relieve this fella?[officer] No, I'm supposed to--
佩尔蒂埃夫人，联邦调查局希望你到办公室来一趟。
Mrs. Pelletier, the FBI would like you to come down to the office.
出什么事了吗？
Did something come up?
远远超出了我的工资等级。
Way above my pay grade.
你想让我和你一起去吗？
You want me to come with you?
我们发现了你父亲的身体。
We found your father's body.
就在州界之内。
Just inside the state line.
我们推测他们当时正前往加拿大的一个口岸。
We assume they were heading for a crossing to Canada.
60英尺高的堤坝上的护栏被撕裂。
Guard rail, 60 feet up on the embankment was splintered.
司机要么失控，要么睡着了。
Driver either lost control or fell asleep.
汽车撞到一棵树上起火了。
The car hit a tree and caught fire.
两人都被烧得面目全非。
Both men were burned beyond recognition.
我们认为他们有同伙。我们现在正在找他。
We think they had an accomplice. We're looking for him now.
你怎么能确定是霍尔布鲁克？
How can you be sure it's Holbrook?
他有三颗金牙，雕刻的图案和你父亲一模一样。
He has three gold teeth with carvings matching your father.
你还好吗？
You all right?
我父亲20年前去世了。
My father died 20 years ago.
嗯。
Mmm.
你爸爸的事我很抱歉。
I'm sorry about your daddy.
我们在电视上看到了。
We saw it on TV.
谢谢你，亲爱的，但他不是我爸爸很长一段时间。
Thank you, sweetie, but he wasn't my daddy for a long time.
我们给你带了点吃的以防你不想做饭。
We brought you some food in case you didn't wanna cook.
让我猜猜，多加了意大利香肠？
Let me guess, extra pepperoni?
- 我很想吃披萨。- 是的！
- I'm definitely in the mood for pizza. - Yes!
你好吗？
How you doing?
我很好。
I'm fine.
我希望你能告诉我真相
I wish you would've told me the truth.
最坏的结果是什么？
What's the worst that could've happened?
- 我们就不会有玛丽了- 你又不知道
- We wouldn't have Mari. - You don't know that.
是的
Yes, I do.
哪个正常的人会和他女儿有关系...
Who in their right mind would get involved with the daughter...
如果你知道我叫霍尔布鲁克，你就不会和我约会了。
If you knew my name was Holbrook, you'd never have gone on a date with me.
你会从另一条路逃跑的
You would've run the other way.
- 你现在会了。- 等等
- You will now. - Hold on.
假装我比你想象的要好，好吗？
Let's pretend that I'm a better person than you think I am, all right?
最好的事情是什么？
What's the best thing that could've happened?
你也许找到了可以信任的人。
You might've found somebody to trust.
一个能帮你度过所有糟糕日子的人
Someone to help you through all the shitty days.
找个人解释你那些奇怪的纹身。
Somebody to explain all your weird tattoos to.
最好的永远不会发生，斯蒂芬。
The best never happens, Stephen.
不管我们有多想要。
No matter how badly we want it.
- 玛丽戈德没事吧- 是啊
- Marigold okay? - Yeah.
她睡着了
She's asleep.
你真的相信吗？
Do you really believe that?
你之前说的...
What you said before about...
最好的永远不会发生。
the best never happening.
因为如果你这么做了，那对我们意味着什么？
Because if you do, what's that mean for us?
我不想让你更难过
Look I-- I don't wanna make this any worse for you.
但你得让我进去海伦娜
But you gotta let me in, Helena.
好吧听着我要去办公室工作了。
Okay, look. I'm gonna go do some work at the office.
可能睡在那边。
Probably sleep over there.
我叫海伦娜·霍尔布鲁克。
My name is Helena Holbrook.
还记得绑架那个女人的人吗
Remember the guy who kidnapped that woman?
大家都叫他沼泽王
The one everybody called The Marsh King?
我是他女儿。
I'm his daughter.
有时候我晚上一个人偷偷溜出去因为我觉得被困住了。
Sometimes I sneak off alone at night because I feel trapped.
就像我不知道我到底属于哪个世界。
Like I can't figure out which world I really belong in.
我很难相信别人因为...
I have trouble trusting people because...
每个人都说我最信任的人
everyone tells me the person I believed in the most
真是个怪物
was really a monster.
我第一次杀人后他给了我这个。
He gave me this after my first kill.
这一次我失手了
And this one when I missed.
这是他教我游泳的地方。
This is the place he taught me to swim.
他给我的名字。
The name he gave me.
这是为了提醒我不要等着做家务。
This to remind me never to wait to do my chores.
这是我父亲唯一想看到的眼泪。
These were the only tears my father ever wanted to see.
你愿意和我约会吗？
Would you like to go out on a date with me?
赶快。我知道。[玛丽戈德]我能做到。
Come on. I know.[Marigold] I can do it.
我一直期待着这一天的到来。
I have been looking forward to this day.
我想是时候把你们介绍给几个人了。
Thought it was time to introduce you to a couple people.
看，爸爸，他们有马。
Look, Daddy, they have horses.
这是克拉克。他会尽最大努力让你叫他爷爷。
This is Clark. He's gonna try his best to get you to call him Grandpa.
让他自己挣来。
Make him earn it.
我一点也不害怕。
That doesn't scare me a bit.
我没有其他人可以把它花在身上。
I've got no one else to spend it on.
很高兴见到你，玛丽戈德。
It is very nice to meet you, Marigold.
你也是，克拉克。
You too, Clark.
我会喜欢这件的。
I'm gonna like this one.
你想看看马吗？
Would you like to see the horses?
谁饿了？
Who's getting hungry?
在我拍了两个小时后，
Two hours after I took that,
我开始接到电话说有个流氓
I started getting calls that some hoodlum
在人们的院子里放烟花。
was setting off fireworks in people's yards.
她从我的一个副手身边跑开，把那条裙子撕成了碎片。
She tore that dress to shreds, running from one of my deputies.
你可以停下来了。
You can stop now.
哦，见鬼，我们还没到你的困难阶段呢。
Oh, hell, we haven't even got to your difficult stage yet.
那是谁？
Who's that?
那是你奶奶。
That's your grandmother.
你一定长得很像她。
You definitely take after her.
我不记得那张照片了。
I don't remember that picture.
它看起来像我们。
It looks like us.
你知道，如果这成为一种习惯，我不会抱怨。
You know, I wouldn't complain if this became a habit.
谢谢你，克拉克。
Thank you, Clark.
随时都行。
Anytime.
嘿。
Hey.
你知道吗，雅各布夺走了我们很多人的信仰，
You know, Jacob took a lot of my people's beliefs,
把它们拧成适合他的样子。
twisted 'em to fit what suited him.
在奥吉布瓦的意思是“拥有”。不是“家人”
Means "owned" in Ojibwa. Not "family."
不要把这两者混淆了。
Don't confuse the two.
嘘--
Sh--
小影子。
Little Shadow.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
我只是去拿点水。
I'm just getting some water.
嘿，进屋时一定要擦干净你的鞋。
Hey, make sure you wipe your feet when you come in the house.
我做到了。
I did.
我会在路上让她下车。
I'll drop her on the way.
回头见。
See you after.
-我们去游泳什么的。-别忘了我的护目镜。
- We'll go swimming or something. - Don't forget my goggles.
我今天下午在底特律参加了一个会议。
I got that conference in Detroit this afternoon.
可能会很晚才回家。
Might be home late.
-你会没事吧？-嗯.
- You gonna be okay? - Mmm.
谢谢。
Thank you.
海伦娜？
Helena?
你好吗？
How you doing?
好的。很好。
Good. Fine.
你们这周末在附近吗？
Are you guys around this weekend?
我在想Jess和Marigold可以有个玩伴。
I was thinking Jess and Marigold could have a playdate.
哦，是啊。我想我们自由了，只是..。
Oh, yeah. I think we're free, just...
抱歉的。是啊，她会喜欢的。
Sorry. Yeah, she'd love that.
星期六怎么样？
How's Saturday? Would she like to come over to our place?
当然了。她一直游到10点，但在那之后...
Of course. She has swim until 10:00 but after that...
你能等一下吗？抱歉的。
Can you hold on a second? Sorry.
你这是在帮倒忙。
You're not helping.
我不应该帮你的。这是你的作业，不是我的。
I'm not supposed to help. This is your homework, not mine.
但你总是帮我。
But you always help.
你可以想办法的
Well, you can figure this out.
你怎么又心情不好了？
Why are you in a bad mood again?
我没有我
I'm not.
我不是故意的。
I don't mean to be.
我们去看书吧。我们会让爸爸早上帮我们完成的
Let's go read. We'll get Daddy to help us finish in the morning.
- 好吗？- 好吧
- Okay? - Okay.
“睡莲铺满了水池的表面
"Water lilies spread over the surface of the pool
就像一张有花图案的地毯。
like a carpet patterned with flowers.
而在这地毯上，躺着一个年轻美丽的女人。
And on this carpet, lay a young and beautiful woman.
母亲哭了，“这是我自己，我看到的，反映在你的眼睛？”
The mother cried, '‘Is this myself I see, reflected in your eyes?'
女儿说...”
And the daughter said..."
嘿，女儿？你错过了入场。
Hey, daughter? You missed your entrance.
海伦娜
Helena.
-  什么事？- 是个洋娃娃。
-  What is it? - It's a doll.
你拿着它玩
You-- You play with it.
像朋友一样。
Like a friend.
她的头发和我一样。
She has hair like me.
小小的海伦娜。
A tiny Helena.
天啊
Oh, God.
玛丽戈德
Marigold!
海伦娜
Helena!
嘿是我
Hey, it's me.
是我
It's me.
天啊你在...
Jesus. What are you...
呃...那是谁的血
Uh... I--Whose blood is that?
没有人的。兔我听到外面有人。
No one's. A rabbit. I heard somebody outside.
也许可以报警
Maybe try calling the police
而不是在黑暗中拿着刀到处跑
instead of running around in the dark with a knife.
-  我得去看看玛丽戈德- 玛丽戈德很好她睡着了
-  I have to check on Marigold. - Marigold's fine. She's asleep.
我刚离开她的房间。
I just left her room.
你看到有人在外面吗？
Did you see anyone out there?
嘿
Hey.
我们要把门锁上，好吗？
We're gonna keep the doors locked, all right?
派几辆警车巡逻。
Get a few cop cars on patrol.
会没事的
It's gonna be okay.
它的头在流血。
It was bleeding from the head.
就像有人先杀了它，然后把它放进陷阱里。
Like someone killed it first, then put it in the snare.
或者它以其他方式受伤了。
Or maybe it got injured some other way.
什么事吓到你了？为什么你觉得还有别的事？
What's got you spooked? Why do you think there's something more?
我觉得他就在这里。
I feel like he's here.
你找到我们的那晚
The night you found us,
当我们走出森林时，
when we came out of the woods,
我很害怕因为他不在我身边。
I was so afraid because he wasn't there with me.
但他来了。
But then he came.
别迷失了方向海伦娜
Don't get lost in this, Helena.
现在他又回来了。
Now he's come back again.
我得告诉他别烦我们。
I have to tell him to leave us alone.
你得试着把他从你的脑海中抹去。
You have got to try to get him out of your head.
永远
For good.
我不确定我能做到。
I'm not sure I can do that.
他怎么可能还活着？
How could he be alive?
我不知道
I don't know.
没有什么比生存的本能更纯洁的了。
There's nothing purer than the instinct to survive.
妈妈！
Mommy!
玛丽戈德
Marigold?
我找不到我的背包了。
I couldn't find my backpack.
哦，不。那个留在这里。
Oh, no, no, no. That stays here.
我想展示给人们看。
I wanna show people.
我们再等等，好吗？
Let's wait a while on that, okay?
好吧
Okay.
你从哪弄来的
Where did you get those?
我以为是你做的。我喜欢他们。
I thought you made them. I like them.
看起来像你和我。
Looks like you and me.
栖息地一直都在你的房间里吗？
Has the habitat been in your room the whole time?
嗯-嗯。
Mm-hmm.
你干吗呢？
What are you doing?
赶快。
Come on.
放学后呆在家里，除非爸爸
Stay inside after school unless Daddy
否则我就在这里，好吗？不管别人说什么，都不要和别人一起去。
or I are here, okay? Don't go with anyone else, no matter what they say.
这是怎么回事？
What's this about?
我就是有这种感觉。
Just felt like it.
你放学后能去接玛丽戈德吗？
Can you pick Marigold up after school?
当然了。
Of course.
为什么？
Why?
我得做点什么。我不能告诉你这是什么。
I have to do something. I can't tell you what it is.
怎么了，海伦娜？
What's going on, Helena?
我知道我没有给你任何理由...
I know I haven't given you any reason to...
请相信我。
please trust me.
我回来后会给你打电话的。
I'll call you when I get back.
从哪里回来？
Back from where?
最后一个秘密，斯蒂芬。
Last secret, Stephen.
我保证。
Promise.
你和玛丽救了我。
You and Mari rescued me.
我可以随心所欲地叫它？
I can call it anything I want?
这是你的了。我把它给你了。
It's yours. I gave it to you.
我给它起名
I name it
海伦娜瀑布。
Helena Falls.
你好，小影子。
Hello, Little Shadow.
我们去散散步吧。
Let's go for a walk.
你怎么找到我的？
How did you find me?
我从未失去过你，小影子。
I never lost you, Little Shadow.
我好怀念那股味道。
I miss that smell.
还有它的味道。
And the taste.
把那个给我。
Gimme that.
我最喜欢的刀。
My favorite knife.
我们以前常来这里露营，你还记得吗？
We used to come camping up here, you remember?
我们整个夏天都在这里躺着。
We'd lay out here all summer long.
抬头仰望天空，
Look up at the sky,
看看谁能数出最多的流星。
see who could count the most shooting stars.
我过去经常作弊和数飞机。
I used to cheat and count airplanes.
你一直都知道我还活着，不是吗？
You knew I was alive the whole time, didn't you?
我不知道这怎么可能。
I didn't know how it was possible.
直到我看到一只三条腿的郊狼。
Not until I saw a three-legged coyote.
为了自由牺牲了自己的腿。
Sacrificed its own leg for freedom.
就像你牺牲了你的牙齿。
Like you sacrificed your teeth.
阿。
Ah.
可能不会通过体检，
Probably won't pass a medical exam,
但它为你赢得了你需要的时间。
but it bought you the time you needed.
你做了一些调查。
You did some digging.
9~10成熟。
Well done.
你没有告诉任何人你的理论吗？
You didn't tell anyone else your theory?
你有没有?
Did you?
真希望你带了玛丽戈德来。
Wish you'd brought Marigold.
跟我说说我的孙女吧。
Tell me about my granddaughter.
我不这样认为。你对她的了解已经够多了。
I don't think so. You know enough about her already.
好吧，我得偷偷看一眼。
Well, I had to take a peek.
你从来没带她来看过我。
You never brought her to visit me.
你根本没来看我。
You didn't visit me at all.
来吧，小影子。
Come on, Little Shadow.
我要给你看点儿东西。
I want to show you something.
你知道吗，玛丽戈德长得很像她。
You know, Marigold looks like her.
你的母亲。
Your mother.
我打赌她和我们一样喜欢水。
I bet she loves the water as much as we do.
这是为了带我们越过边境。
That's to take us across the border.
我们三个人。
The three of us.
去加拿大，我们又可以成为一家人了。
To Canada, we can be a family again.
我有一个家庭。
I have a family.
你有一个女儿。
You have a daughter.
还有一个丈夫。
And a husband.
我们一起建立了自己的生活。
We've built a life together.
你对这种生活满意吗？
Are you happy with that life?
不总是这样。
Not always.
你有没有想过当时是什么样子
Do you ever think back to what it was like
当我们住在这里的时候？
when we lived here?
-我知道。-我们可以再拥有一次。
- I do. - We can have it all again.
我记得你四岁的时候，
I remember when you were four years old,
你可以闭上眼睛
you could shut your eyes
你从水声中知道你在哪里，
and you knew where you were from the sound of the water,
从树木的气味来看，
from the smell of the trees,
以及你脚下的土地的感觉。
and the feel of the ground beneath your feet.
就像变魔术一样。
It was like magic.
这就是我们的归宿。
This is where we belong.
这是我们的家。
It's our home.
我们在这里的生活
Our life here
是完美的。
was perfect.
不是的！
No!
[贝丝]不！
[Beth] No!
你再也不要从我身边跑开了！
Don't you ever run away from me again!
好吧?你听到了吗？
Okay? You hear me?
我没有...
I wasn't--
完美？
Perfect?
对我母亲来说不是。
Not for my mother.
嗯，可能是这样的。
Well, it could've been.
多么?
How?
-你绑架了她.-没有。我们一起私奔了。
- You kidnapped her. - No. We ran away together.
这只是她决定离开时说的话。
That's just something she said when she decided to leave.
-你开枪打死了那个人.-我在试着撞引擎.
- You shot that man. - I was trying to hit the engine.
你永远不会错过的。
You never would have missed.
我没打中。
I missed.
你听过很多关于我的故事。
You've been told a bunch of stories about me.
这些都不是真的。我从来都不是沼泽之王，直到他们说我是。
They're not true. I never was the Marsh King, until they said I was.
我知道，我们很幸福。
I know this, we were happy.
你当时很开心。
You were happy.
我要说的是，带上玛丽戈德，让她自己去看看。
All I'm saying, bring Marigold, let her see for herself.
我不能那么做。
I can't do that.
我不会的。
I won't.
对不起。这就是它结束的地方。
I'm sorry. This is where it ends.
我不该来这里的。
I shouldn't have come here.
我很高兴我这么做了。
I'm glad I did.
现在我必须回家和家人在一起。
Now I have to go home to my family.
请不要再靠近他们了。
Please don't come near them again.
-它不需要是这样的。-的确如此。
- It doesn't need to be like this. - It does.
好吧。
Okay.
我明白。
I understand.
你永远是我的小影子。
You'll always be my Little Shadow.
我得走了。
I have to go.
克拉克?
Clark?
-你在这里干什么？-我也想问你同样的问题.
- What are you doing here? - Could ask you the same thing.
斯蒂芬给我打了电话。他很担心。
Stephen called me. He was worried.
我对你说的话有一种预感。
And I just had a hunch after what you said.
-他在吗？-我们回去吧我会在路上告诉你的。
- Is he here? - Let's go back. I'll tell you on the way.
海伦娜，他来过吗？
Helena, was he here?
但他已经走了。
But he's gone.
克拉克。克拉克。
Clark. Clark.
克拉克。哦，上帝。哦，上帝。
Clark. Oh, God. Oh, God.
克拉克，看着我，好吗？
Clark, look at me, okay?
克拉克。克拉克，留下来陪我。
Clark. Clark, stay with me.
你告诉他了-你要来这里？-没有，我什么都没说。
You told him - you were coming here? - No, I didn't say anything.
拜托，看着我。
Please, look at me.
克拉克，我就在这里。
Clark, I'm right here.
克拉克，等一下。克拉克，请等一下。
Clark, hold on. Please, Clark, hold on.
你一定说了什么。
You must've said something.
让你的继父感到好奇。
Make your stepfather curious.
足以让他一个人一路游荡到这里。
Enough to wander out here all this way by himself.
离我们远点。你做了什么？
Just get away from us. What have you done?
拜托，克拉克。请。赶快。
Please, Clark. Please. Come on.
赶快。请。
Come on. Please.
嗯，你现在帮不了他了。
Well, there's nothing you can do to help him now.
不是的！
No!
你宁愿狼活着也不愿我们活着？
You'd rather the wolf lived than us?
你想让它把你喂给它的小狗？
You want it to feed you to its pup?
现在我得自己去找玛丽戈德了。
Now I have to get Marigold on my own.
不是的！别碰她！
No! Don't you touch her!
我们仍然可以成为一家人。
We can still all be a family.
这就是我想要的。
It's all I want.
我很快就会回来和玛丽戈德在一起。
I'll be back with Marigold soon.
不是的！不，不。
No! No, no.
不是的！
No!
海伦娜。
Helena.
把绳子缠在你身上。
Wrap the rope around you.
他说我可以上来了吗？
Did he say I could come up?
我不在乎，我会把你弄出来的。
I don't care, I'm getting you out of there.
我抓住你了，我的海伦娜。
I've got you, my Helena.
你不会有事的。
You're gonna be fine.
因为你比我强壮。
Because you're stronger than me.
比我更勇敢。
Braver than me.
请。
Please.
克拉克。
Clark.
我太抱歉了。
I'm so sorry.
我会回来找你的。
I'll come back for you.
所有的河流都会弯曲，海伦娜。
All rivers bend, Helena.
血是热的还是冷的？
Is the blood warm or cold?
冷的。冷的。
Cold. Cold.
那么你必须走得更快。
Then you must move faster.
跑步还是走路？
Running or walking?
跑步。
Running.
如果你害怕，
And if you were afraid,
为你的生命奔跑，
running for your life,
你会跑到哪里去？
where would you run?
到了没人能看到我的地方。
To where no one could see me.
你知道你教会了我什么吗。
You know what you taught me.
你很好，只是个皮肉伤。
You're fine, it's just a flesh wound.
现在..。
Now...
这对玛丽戈尔德有什么好处？
what good will it do Marigold
如果她的母亲躺在沼泽的底部腐烂？
if her mother is lying rotting in the bottom of the marsh?
她需要你。
She needs you.
想想什么对你女儿最好。
Just think about what's best for your daughter.
好吧?
Okay?
不是的！
No!
你进来的那艘船。让我看看。
The boat you came in. Show me.
继续。
Go on.
我等了一辈子就想再见到你。
I waited my whole life to see you again.
我不确定当我这么做的时候我会有什么感觉。
I wasn't sure what I would feel when I did.
-你有什么感觉，小影子？-别那么叫我.
- What do you feel, Little Shadow? - Don't call me that.
现在不是了。
Not anymore.
我以前以为你这么说是因为我一直在你身边。
I used to think you said it because I was always beside you.
现在我意识到你的意思是，
Now I realize you just meant,
就像任何影子一样，如果没有你，我就不会存在。
like any shadow, I wouldn't exist if you weren't standing there.
我走后，你母亲对你做了一件事。
Your mother did a job on you after I was gone.
不，她没有。
No, she didn't.
我这辈子都没怎么跟她说过话。
I barely spoke to her my whole life.
我也把一切都怪到她头上。我从来不相信她。
I blamed her for everything too. I never believed her.
你真的觉得她关心你就像我关心你一样？
You really think she cared about you the way I care about you?
她不会拿枪指着我。
She wouldn't have a gun on me.
她本可以逃跑的。
She could have run.
逃走了。
Gotten away.
她留下来是为了保护我。
She stayed to protect me.
现在我知道了，她才是坚强的那个。
Now I know, she was the strong one.
她很虚弱。
She was weak.
不是的。
No.
一个把女人拖进荒野的男人是软弱的。
A man who drags a woman into the wilderness is weak.
小心点，小影子。
Careful, Little Shadow.
You forget all the things that I did for you.
我在笼子里度过的岁月
The years I spent in a cage
因为我是为你回来的
'cause I came back for you.
你会为玛丽戈德做什么？
What would you do for Marigold?
我愿意为她而死。
I'd die for her.
爸爸！
Daddy!
赶快。赶快。
Come on. Come on.
睡莲散落在池面上
"Water lilies spread over the surface of the pool
就像一块有花朵图案的地毯。
like a carpet patterned with flowers.
在这块地毯上躺着一位强壮美丽的女人。
And on this carpet lay a strong and beautiful woman.
母亲叫道：“我看到的就是你眼中的我吗？”
The mother cried, '‘Is this myself I see, reflected in your eyes?'
女儿说……“
And the daughter said..."
“我看到的是我吗？”
"Is it me I see,
反映在你的身上吗？“
mirrored in yours?"
然后，孩子像一只强大的天鹅一样站了起来
"Then the child rose in the shape of a mighty swan
展开她有力的翅膀。“
and spread her powerful wings."
我不恨你。
I don't hate you.
我并不同情你。
I don't pity you.
我只记得你的功课。
I just remember your lesson.
永远保护我的家人。
Always protect my family.